<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>business on WhiteMatterTech</title>
    <link>https://whitematter.tech/categories/business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in business on WhiteMatterTech</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://whitematter.tech/brain.jpg</url>
      <link>https://whitematter.tech/brain.jpg</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://whitematter.tech/categories/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How To Do An In-Place Upgrade To Windows Server 2022</title>
      <link>https://whitematter.tech/posts/how-to-do-an-in-place-upgrade-to-windows-server-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whitematter.tech/posts/how-to-do-an-in-place-upgrade-to-windows-server-2022/</guid>
      <description>I recently had to upgrade two domain controllers to Windows Server 2022. The main controller was still on Windows Server 2016 while the secondary was Windows Server 2019. Both in-place upgrades went without issue.
Both servers were running Hyper-V, Bitlocker, and AD Controller. The 2019 server had an SMTP server that it was running, but Microsoft has deprecated the SMTP stack and associated management tools, including the IIS tools. There very well may be other deprecated software or tools, and I highly recommend searching for specific functionality you utilize on your Win Servers before attempting the upgrade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Note on Leading Geographically Dispersed Teams</title>
      <link>https://whitematter.tech/posts/a-quick-note-on-leading-geographically-dispersed-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whitematter.tech/posts/a-quick-note-on-leading-geographically-dispersed-teams/</guid>
      <description>The ability for geographically dispersed teams to interact, engage, and collaborate effectively is a concern for increasing numbers of corporations, teams, and leadership, especially in the post-COVID-19 era workplace. Adoption of technological solutions for computer-mediated communication can mitigate some of the inherent complexities and difficulties of the geographical dispersion problem, and research teams have increased efforts to both understand the problem and design groupware solutions to support virtual team collaboration (Morrison-Smith &amp;amp; Ruiz, 2020).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
