<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>networking on WhiteMatterTech</title>
    <link>/categories/networking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in networking on WhiteMatterTech</description>
    <image>
      <url>brain.jpg</url>
      <link>brain.jpg</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Split-Brain DNS&#39; for Internal HTTPS with Let&#39;s Encrypt</title>
      <link>/posts/https-for-homelab-internal-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/https-for-homelab-internal-resources/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this previous post, I showed how to connect to a Unifi router with HTTPS, effectively ridding you of the tedious words, &amp;ldquo;Your connection is not private.&amp;rdquo; However, the method shown in that post directs your connection to an external DNS server (e.g., CloudFlare) in order to resolve your Unifi router. This adds some latency by requiring your traffic to flow out and in rather than staying local. Additionally, it requires opening some ports externally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Run AlienVault OSSIM as a VM on Unraid</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-run-alienvault-ossim-as-a-vm-on-unraid/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-run-alienvault-ossim-as-a-vm-on-unraid/</guid>
      <description>Introduction For this post, I will show you how to setup Unraid to run AlienVault OSSIM as a VM. OSSIM is a powerful open-source SIEM that you can leverage on your network for free. I use OSSIM for network-wide vulnerability scanning and endpoint host intrusion detection.
OSSIM&amp;rsquo;s integrated HIDS is a fork from OSSEC. Additionally, OSSIM integrates with Open Threat Exchange (OTX), which can be installed on Windows, Mac, and Linux endpoints and servers for an up-to-date, open-source vulnerability scanning tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Connect to Your Unifi Dream Machine or UNVR with SSL from Let&#39;s Encrypt</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-connect-to-your-unifi-dream-machine-or-unvr-with-ssl-from-lets-encrypt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-connect-to-your-unifi-dream-machine-or-unvr-with-ssl-from-lets-encrypt/</guid>
      <description>Update 05/09/2022: The conclusions of this post will route your traffic externally, requiring your local devices to reach external DNS servers (e.g., in my case, CloudFlare) in order to resolve your Unifi Gateway address. If you want to handle all of this completely locally/internally, check out my newer post: HTTPS for Internal Resources
  Alright, if you have a Unifi device like a Dream Machine, Dream Machine Pro, UNVR, CloudKey, or other device, you likely have been met with the dreaded red triangle followed by the tedious words, &amp;ldquo;Your connection is not private.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Easily Run A Reverse Proxy using Docker</title>
      <link>/posts/run-a-reverse-proxy-using-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/run-a-reverse-proxy-using-docker/</guid>
      <description>Reverse proxies are powerful tools used typically to forward client traffic to a server. In contrast to a forward proxy, a reverse proxy sits in front of web servers or other servers and forwards client traffic to the appropriate server. In this post, I will show you how to easily setup a reverse proxy using Docker, forward the necessary ports to the reverse proxy, and configure the reverse proxy to forward traffic to various servers on your network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Add VLAN Segmentation for HomeKit IoT Devices with Unifi</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-add-vlan-segmentation-for-homekit-iot-devices-with-unifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-add-vlan-segmentation-for-homekit-iot-devices-with-unifi/</guid>
      <description>IoT Overview The smart world of Internet-of-Things (IoT) devices is ever growing. From everyday lightbulbs to the sprinkler out front, just about every household appliance and utility has a smart-counterpart. For example, my smart home is fully Apple HomeKit compatible and consists of a Hue bridge with lightbulbs, Lutron Caseta smart dimmers/switches, Eve Aqua outdoor water hose control, iSmartGate garage door opener, Schlage deadbolt, Eve motion sensor, Sonos speakers throughout the house, a Vocolinc oil diffuser, Vocolionc power strip, a couple iRobot Roomba vacuum cleaners, some Vocolinc pluggable outlets, an Ecobee thermostat to replace each analog thermostat in the house, and a Unifi G4 Doorbell (the doorbell is not technically compatible with HomeKit, but I added support with a third-party tool known as &amp;ldquo;Homebridge&amp;rdquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Harden Your Network Security for Your In-Home Web Hosting</title>
      <link>/posts/network-hardening-webhosting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/network-hardening-webhosting/</guid>
      <description>Overview The purpose of this post is to provide some tips to address some network security concerns when hosting an externally-facing web server from a device within your home network. For this post, I will be using Unifi networking gear. My screenshots will be of the Unifi controller on my Unifi Dream Machine Pro (UDMP), but I will do my best to overview the concepts so you can replicate with your own networking gear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use pfSense and Unifi to Anonymize and Encrypt VLAN Tagged Traffic</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-use-pfsense-and-unifi-to-anonymize-and-encrypt-vlan-tagged-traffic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-use-pfsense-and-unifi-to-anonymize-and-encrypt-vlan-tagged-traffic/</guid>
      <description>This post aims to show you how to use pfSense within a Unifi network behind a Unifi Gateway [in my case, the gateway is the Unifi Dream Machine Pro (hereafter referred to as UDMP)]. I will explain my current network configuration including applicable subnets, VLANs, and wireless SSIDs needed to make this setup successful. The end goal is to be able to add a client on my Unifi network to a particular VLAN either by joining this client wirelessly to a particular SSID or by tagging the client&amp;rsquo;s physical port to that VLAN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Host Your Own Free Wordpress Site with Traefik and Docker</title>
      <link>/posts/hosting-your-own-site-with-traefik-and-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/hosting-your-own-site-with-traefik-and-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>Update 03/20/2022: I no longer host my site with Traefik, and my site is no longer built on WordPress. I now host my site internally using an Nginx proxy hosted in Docker. My site is built with Hugo. Learn more about my transition from WordPress to Hugo on my post here: Migrating from WordPress to Hugo
  My first post will, appropriately, show you how to build your own self-hosted Wordpress site utilizing Docker (just like this site)!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
