<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>research on WhiteMatterTech</title>
    <link>/tags/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in research on WhiteMatterTech</description>
    <image>
      <url>brain.jpg</url>
      <link>brain.jpg</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Arduino MQ-3B Ethanol Sensor: Behavioral Neuroscience Research</title>
      <link>/posts/arduino-mq-3b-ethanol-sensor-behavioral-neuroscience-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/arduino-mq-3b-ethanol-sensor-behavioral-neuroscience-research/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Recently, I had the opportunity to collaborate with a university research lab to build some vapor sensors to roughly measure ethanol (EtOH) vapor within an operant chamber. This project was a lot of fun.
With extremely limited circuit documentation on the web and never having personally used Arduino before, there were a lot of interesting hiccups I ran into. Overall, this project was a bit out of my wheelhouse, but with much determination, the finished product turned out rather nicely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Usability Evaluations: Findability</title>
      <link>/posts/usability-evaluations-findability/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/usability-evaluations-findability/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This review investigated findability and its relationship to usability and usability evaluations. Definitions of usability, findability, usability evaluations, and other sub-components of these terms including navigability are discussed, and the importance of research studies using similar terminologies is considered. A series of six usability evaluation studies is presented, and the terminologies presented in each are described. Goals, findings, and conclusions of each study are considered, and applications from the conclusions are drawn.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
