<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>encrypt on WhiteMatterTech</title>
    <link>/tags/encrypt/</link>
    <description>Recent content in encrypt on WhiteMatterTech</description>
    <image>
      <url>brain.jpg</url>
      <link>brain.jpg</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/encrypt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tails OS with Encrypted Persistence on Unraid as a VM</title>
      <link>/posts/tails-os-with-encrypted-persistence-on-unraid-as-a-vm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tails-os-with-encrypted-persistence-on-unraid-as-a-vm/</guid>
      <description>This post will show you how to run Tails OS as a VM with the Persistence feature enabled.
Running Tails as a VM is not recommended generally as it defeats many of the security features in Tails. For example, virtualization requires that you trust the hypervisor host, as the hypervisor has extra privileges over a VM that can reduce security and privacy of the VM.
I recommend reading Tails&amp;rsquo;s official documentation about virtualization considerations before continuing: https://tails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use pfSense and Unifi to Anonymize and Encrypt VLAN Tagged Traffic</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-use-pfsense-and-unifi-to-anonymize-and-encrypt-vlan-tagged-traffic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-use-pfsense-and-unifi-to-anonymize-and-encrypt-vlan-tagged-traffic/</guid>
      <description>This post aims to show you how to use pfSense within a Unifi network behind a Unifi Gateway [in my case, the gateway is the Unifi Dream Machine Pro (hereafter referred to as UDMP)]. I will explain my current network configuration including applicable subnets, VLANs, and wireless SSIDs needed to make this setup successful. The end goal is to be able to add a client on my Unifi network to a particular VLAN either by joining this client wirelessly to a particular SSID or by tagging the client&amp;rsquo;s physical port to that VLAN.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
