<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>tutorials on WhiteMatterTech</title>
    <link>https://whitematter.tech/tags/tutorials/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tutorials on WhiteMatterTech</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://whitematter.tech/brain.jpg</url>
      <link>https://whitematter.tech/brain.jpg</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://whitematter.tech/tags/tutorials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Run Graylog with Docker Compose on Unraid</title>
      <link>https://whitematter.tech/posts/run-graylog-with-docker-compose-on-unraid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whitematter.tech/posts/run-graylog-with-docker-compose-on-unraid/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Logging and traffic monitoring are of utmost importance in information security. Having searchable stored logs can allow visibility into a variety of critical activities related to a data breach.
For example, individual computer event logs can provide insight into an attacker&amp;rsquo;s lateral movement within an environment. Active Directory authentication logs can provide more detail into this lateral movement and even help to establish a timeline of this movement. Firewall logs can provide insight into an attacker&amp;rsquo;s first contact or the first time an attacker utilized a particular command or control domain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating from Wordpress to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://whitematter.tech/posts/migrating-from-wordpress-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whitematter.tech/posts/migrating-from-wordpress-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Introduction When I initially began posting publicly on this site, my goal was to be able to host my site fully with Docker for containerization. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t experienced any other decent blogging platform besides WordPress at the time, and I was bent on getting WordPress self-hosted with Docker.
This goal was achieved, and my first public post details how I used docker-compose to deploy my blog using containers for WordPress and Traefik.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arduino MQ-3B Ethanol Sensor: Behavioral Neuroscience Research</title>
      <link>https://whitematter.tech/posts/arduino-mq-3b-ethanol-sensor-behavioral-neuroscience-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whitematter.tech/posts/arduino-mq-3b-ethanol-sensor-behavioral-neuroscience-research/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Recently, I had the opportunity to collaborate with a university research lab to build some vapor sensors to roughly measure ethanol (EtOH) vapor within an operant chamber. This project was a lot of fun.
With extremely limited circuit documentation on the web and never having personally used Arduino before, there were a lot of interesting hiccups I ran into. Overall, this project was a bit out of my wheelhouse, but with much determination, the finished product turned out rather nicely.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
