<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>unifi on WhiteMatterTech</title>
    <link>/tags/unifi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in unifi on WhiteMatterTech</description>
    <image>
      <url>brain.jpg</url>
      <link>brain.jpg</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/unifi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Connect to Your Unifi Dream Machine or UNVR with SSL from Let&#39;s Encrypt</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-connect-to-your-unifi-dream-machine-or-unvr-with-ssl-from-lets-encrypt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-connect-to-your-unifi-dream-machine-or-unvr-with-ssl-from-lets-encrypt/</guid>
      <description>Update 05/09/2022: The conclusions of this post will route your traffic externally, requiring your local devices to reach external DNS servers (e.g., in my case, CloudFlare) in order to resolve your Unifi Gateway address. If you want to handle all of this completely locally/internally, check out my newer post: HTTPS for Internal Resources
  Alright, if you have a Unifi device like a Dream Machine, Dream Machine Pro, UNVR, CloudKey, or other device, you likely have been met with the dreaded red triangle followed by the tedious words, &amp;ldquo;Your connection is not private.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Easily Run A Reverse Proxy using Docker</title>
      <link>/posts/run-a-reverse-proxy-using-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/run-a-reverse-proxy-using-docker/</guid>
      <description>Reverse proxies are powerful tools used typically to forward client traffic to a server. In contrast to a forward proxy, a reverse proxy sits in front of web servers or other servers and forwards client traffic to the appropriate server. In this post, I will show you how to easily setup a reverse proxy using Docker, forward the necessary ports to the reverse proxy, and configure the reverse proxy to forward traffic to various servers on your network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use pfSense and Unifi to Anonymize and Encrypt VLAN Tagged Traffic</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-use-pfsense-and-unifi-to-anonymize-and-encrypt-vlan-tagged-traffic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-use-pfsense-and-unifi-to-anonymize-and-encrypt-vlan-tagged-traffic/</guid>
      <description>This post aims to show you how to use pfSense within a Unifi network behind a Unifi Gateway [in my case, the gateway is the Unifi Dream Machine Pro (hereafter referred to as UDMP)]. I will explain my current network configuration including applicable subnets, VLANs, and wireless SSIDs needed to make this setup successful. The end goal is to be able to add a client on my Unifi network to a particular VLAN either by joining this client wirelessly to a particular SSID or by tagging the client&amp;rsquo;s physical port to that VLAN.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
