<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>wordpress on WhiteMatterTech</title>
    <link>/tags/wordpress/</link>
    <description>Recent content in wordpress on WhiteMatterTech</description>
    <image>
      <url>brain.jpg</url>
      <link>brain.jpg</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/wordpress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Migrating from Wordpress to Hugo</title>
      <link>/posts/migrating-from-wordpress-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/migrating-from-wordpress-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Introduction When I initially began posting publicly on this site, my goal was to be able to host my site fully with Docker for containerization. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t experienced any other decent blogging platform besides WordPress at the time, and I was bent on getting WordPress self-hosted with Docker.
This goal was achieved, and my first public post details how I used docker-compose to deploy my blog using containers for WordPress and Traefik.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Easily Run A Reverse Proxy using Docker</title>
      <link>/posts/run-a-reverse-proxy-using-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/run-a-reverse-proxy-using-docker/</guid>
      <description>Reverse proxies are powerful tools used typically to forward client traffic to a server. In contrast to a forward proxy, a reverse proxy sits in front of web servers or other servers and forwards client traffic to the appropriate server. In this post, I will show you how to easily setup a reverse proxy using Docker, forward the necessary ports to the reverse proxy, and configure the reverse proxy to forward traffic to various servers on your network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Host Your Own Free Wordpress Site with Traefik and Docker</title>
      <link>/posts/hosting-your-own-site-with-traefik-and-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/hosting-your-own-site-with-traefik-and-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>Update 03/20/2022: I no longer host my site with Traefik, and my site is no longer built on WordPress. I now host my site internally using an Nginx proxy hosted in Docker. My site is built with Hugo. Learn more about my transition from WordPress to Hugo on my post here: Migrating from WordPress to Hugo
  My first post will, appropriately, show you how to build your own self-hosted Wordpress site utilizing Docker (just like this site)!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
